arbormemorial.ca 2019-06-18

# Privacy Statement | Arbor Memorial Inc.

**Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement describes how Arbor Memorial Inc. and its related companies and affiliates (collectively, “Arbor”, “we”, “us”, “our”), may collect, use and disclose personal information. This Privacy Statement applies to any personal information we collect or receive about you, from any source. Reference to “you” or “your” includes your personal representative.

This Privacy Statement may be updated by Arbor giving reasonable notice of the revised terms (including by mail, e-mail or by posting on this website). This Privacy Statement may be supplemented or modified by consents you provide to Arbor, and by agreements you enter into with Arbor from time to time.

**Personal Information**

‘Personal information’ means information about an identifiable individual. Examples of personal information that we may collect, use and disclose include your contact information (name, address, phone number, email address), identifying information (e.g. place and date of birth and your social insurance number), your billing information (credit card number or banking information), information about the products and services which you have ordered, your interest in obtaining information about Arbor’s products and services (or the products or services of others), information about your personal representative, caregivers, family or friends, and other information that you may provide to us or that we may collect from other sources in the course of our relationship with you.

**Our collection, use and disclosure of personal information**

In most cases, we will collect personal information directly from you when you purchase or interact with us about a product or service that we offer or provide (for example, when you email us or contact us through our website or when you enter into certain contests or promotions with us). Occasionally, we may collect personal information from a third party based on your consent or as otherwise permitted by law.

We identify the purposes for which we may collect, use and disclose your personal information at the time that we collect such information or by referring to this Privacy Statement. Such purposes for the collection, use and disclosure of personal information include, but are not limited to:

  * Making and administering your funeral and burial arrangements and contracts, and delivering products and services to you, including assisting your personal representative, caregivers, family or friends;
  * Informing you about our products and services, and the products and services of our affiliates and partners, except where you have opted out or unsubscribed from receiving such information;
  * Arranging or administering an annuity or insurance contract for you (e.g. with Assurant Life of Canada or National Assistance, Inc.);
  * Internal business purposes, such as responding to your questions and inquiries, and administering and improving our customer service, website and other services;
  * Establishing, managing or terminating your employment relationship (including certain agency or contracting relationships) with Arbor or as an applicant for employment with Arbor;
  * Contacting you in respect of any promotional contests you have entered into with Arbor;
  * Sharing obituaries and accompanying photograph(s) with third party publishers (such as newspapers);
  * Creating an online memorial including but not limited to photograph(s) and/or video(s) where others may share condolences, photograph(s) and/or video(s) and other content; and
  * Additional purposes which are required or permitted by law, or that are identified at or before the time that the information is used for such additional purposes.

We will typically obtain your express consent for such purposes at or before the time that we collect, use or disclose your personal information, except where permitted or required by law. Arbor only shares your information with third parties working on its behalf. Third parties are not authorized to use your information for any purpose other than that for which it has been shared by Arbor.

Arbor’s facilities, related companies, and affiliates may share personal information with each other in relation to the purposes above or that you have consented to. We may also share your personal information with third party service providers as necessary for them to provide services on our behalf (e.g. data management and storage services). Some service providers may be located outside of Canada where personal information may be subject to the laws of those jurisdictions. To obtain information about Arbor's affiliates or other organizations which may have access to your personal information under Arbor's control, please contact our Chief Privacy Officer as indicated below.

Subject to contractual requirements and applicable law, you may withdraw or vary your consent to Arbor's collection, use or disclosure of your personal information at any time, by giving reasonable notice to Arbor by contacting the Chief Privacy Officer as indicated below.  Arbor may advise you of the implications of the withdrawal or variation - for example, the withdrawal of consent may not allow Arbor to provide you with information regarding its products or services. You may opt-out of receiving promotional and related electronic communications from Arbor by using the unsubscribe mechanism included with such communications.

**Retention and Safeguarding of Personal Information**

Arbor retains personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected, as permitted or required by law (e.g. internal business or management or legal purposes of Arbor).  We have implemented physical, organizational, contractual and technological safeguards designed to help protect your personal information against loss or theft, and unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.

**Cookies, Website Information and Advertising**

Arbor may use persistent anonymous cookies to collect information about your browsing history on our website. We may use that information to customize your experience on our website and to deliver our advertisements to you on other websites that you may visit via the Google Display Network. A cookie is a small data file that websites commonly write to your computer. You may choose to set your computer to reject cookies. However, by not accepting cookies, you may not be able to use all the features of our site.

In addition, you may opt-out of Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) members’ online behavioural advertising by reading more and following the instructions provided here: <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>. These opt-outs are valid only for the computer and browser combination used to opt-out. If you opt-out of NAI third-party advertising network, you will no longer receive ads based on your browsing history from that network. You may, however, continue to receive generalized online advertising.

From time to time, we collect certain information relating to visits and use of our websites, including but not limited to Internet Protocol addresses, Internet domain names, the web browser and operating system used to access the website, the files visited, the time spent in each file, and the time and date of each visit. We use this information to help identify the visitor, gather broad demographic information to improve our website, for example by enhancing pages or features that are visited frequently. We may share this information with our affiliates or other third party companies to provide them with an indication of the amount of interest in our website for advertising purposes and to help us make technical improvements.

**Access and Correction of Personal Information**

You may request access to your personal information, or request correction to your personal information or challenge its completeness, by contacting the Chief Privacy Officer in writing as indicated below. We will respond to your request and provide access to any personal information that we have collected, used or disclosed, as required by law. We will attempt to respond to your request within thirty (30) days. We will advise you in writing if we cannot meet your requests within this time limit.

**Contact us**

Our Chief Privacy Officer is accountable for our compliance with this privacy statement and applicable privacy laws. All comments, questions, concerns or complaints regarding your personal information should be forwarded to our Chief Privacy Officer as follows: Chief Privacy Officer, Arbor Memorial Services Inc., 2 Jane Street, Toronto, Ontario M6S 4W8, Tel: 1-800-465-1270, email: [cpo@arbormemorial.com](mailto:cpo@arbormemorial.com).

Updated May 2018
